<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<top-song xmlns="http://marklogic.com/MLU/top-songs">
  <!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Southern_Nights_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.-->
  <title href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Southern_Nights_(song)" xmlns:ts="http://marklogic.com/MLU/top-songs">Southern Nights</title>
  <artist href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glen_Campbell" xmlns:ts="http://marklogic.com/MLU/top-songs">Glen Campbell</artist>
  <weeks last="1977-04-30">
    <week>1977-04-30</week>
  </weeks>
  <album>Southern Nights</album>
  <released>January 1977 ( U.S. )</released>
  <formats>
    <format>7"</format>
  </formats>
  <recorded>1976</recorded>
  <genres>
    <genre>Country</genre>
  </genres>
  <lengths>
    <length>3:00</length>
  </lengths>
  <label>Capitol Records 4376</label>
  <writers>
    <writer>Allen Toussaint</writer>
  </writers>
  <producers>
    <producer>Gary Klein</producer>
  </producers>
  <descr>
    <p>"Southern Nights" is a song written by Allen Toussaint and
    most famously recorded by country-pop singer Glen Campbell. The
    song enjoyed immense popularity with both country and pop
    audiences when Campbell covered it in 1977.</p>
    <p>Campbell had been a leader in crossover music during the
    1960s and 1970s, and continued that trend when he recorded
    Toussaint's "Southern Nights." Toussaint recalled his memories
    of visiting relatives in the Louisiana backwoods when writing
    the song; often, while listening to stories from his elderly
    relatives, the young Toussaint would look up in the clear
    nighttime, star-filled sky.</p>
    <p>Campbell listened to Toussaint's recording of the song and
    identified with its lyrics, as it reminded him of his days as
    an Arkansas farm youth. "My dad told me when I was a kid,
    'You're having the best time of your life, and you don't even
    known it.' Sure enough, he was right."</p>
    <p>After some modifications to the lyrics, Campbell recorded
    the song.</p>
    <p>Released in January 1977, "Southern Nights" immediately
    caught on with both country and pop audiences. The song spent
    the late winter and early spring climbling both the 
    <i>Billboard magazine</i>Hot Country Singles and Billboard Hot
    100 charts.</p>
    <p>Toward the end of March, the song spent two weeks at No. 1
    on the country chart, and at the end of April, one week at No.
    1 on the Hot 100. On both charts, it was Campbell's final #1
    song, his fifth on the country chart, and second on the pop
    chart. In addition, the song rose to #1 on the adult
    contemporary chart, where it remained for four weeks; this was
    Campbell's seventh #1 on this chart.</p>
    <p>"Southern Nights" was Campbell's final Top 10 hit on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100. However, he would continue to enjoy
    success on the country chart, scoring Top 10 hits through the
    end of 1989.</p>
    <p>"Southern Nights" was certified gold for sales of 1 million
    units by the Recording Industry Association of America. [3]</p>
    <p>The song was nominated for Song of the Year in 1977 by the
    Country Music Association, but did not win.</p>
  </descr>
</top-song>